乔伊 你在吗
Joey? Are you in there?
- 天哪 是瑞秋   - 乔伊 你得跟她谈一谈
- Oh, my God, that's Rachel.     - Joey, you have to talk to her.
不行 经过那晚的事之后 感觉真的太奇怪了
No, I can't. Not after the other night. It's just... It's too weird, okay?
别告诉她我在这里
Don't tell her I'm here.
别吃那个
Don't eat that.
- 嘿   - 瑞秋
- Hey.     - Rach.
- 嘿 瑞秋   - 乔伊在吗
- Hey, Rachel.     - Is Joey here?
- 我没有看到他 你呢    - 没有
- I don't see him. You see him?     - I don't see him.
或许他在我糖碗里 乔伊 没有
Maybe he's in the sugar bowl. Joey? Nope.
至少你们能逗彼此笑
Well, at least you make each other laugh.
- 怎么了    - 我一直没见过他 自从…
- What's up?     - Well, I haven't seen him since that night...
他说他怎么…你们知道的…
...that he told me how he, you know...
我不知道 我想他在避我
I don't know, I think he's avoiding me.
为什么地板上会有贝果
Why is that bagel on the floor?
- 我们在玩游戏   - 钱德没穿衣服吗
- We were playing a game.     - Ew, was Chandler naked?
像是在玩套圈圈游戏吗
Sort of like a ring-toss kind of situation?
- 没错   - 什么 不
- Sure.     - What? No. No.
好吧 听着 如果你们看到乔伊 能不能告诉他…
All right, well, listen. If you see Joey, will you just tell him that, uh?
告诉他我很想他
Tell him I miss him.
- 好吧 你听到了吗    - 是啊 裸体贝果游戏
- Okay. Did you hear that?     - Yeah. That naked bagel game? Heh.
我不知道 那个洞真的很小
Dude, I don't know. That's a pretty small hole.
- 你得跟她谈一谈   - 我没办法
- Honey, you've gotta talk to her.     - I can't.
你们不知道被拒绝的感觉…
You guys don't know what it's like to put yourself out there like that...
有多难受
...and then just get shot down.
我不知道那种感觉
I don't know what that's like?
我在25岁前一直以为"我爱你"的反应是"喔 天啊"
Up until I was 25, I thought the only response to "I love you" was "Oh, crap."
我没有被拒绝过
Hello. No rejection?
我在减肥营时被拒绝过
I got shot down at fat camp.
天啊 饥饿的孩子们 真的很残忍
Boy, kids are mean when they're hungry.
我该怎么办
All right, so, what do I do?
她是瑞秋 你永远都不要跟她说话吗
This is Rachel. What are you gonna do, never talk to her again?
那很奇怪 也很尴尬 但至少你得试试看
I know it's weird and it's awkward, but you gotta at least try.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
我忘了这个曾套在你的…
Whoa. I almost forgot this was on your...
我们没有玩它
We didn't play it.
# 没有人告诉你活着有多累 #
# So no one told you life was gonna be this way #
# 上班受罪 口袋空空 爱情变累赘 #
# Your job's a joke, you're broke, your love life's D.O.A. #
# 寂寞又潦倒 受气又受累 #
# It's like you're always stuck in second gear #
# 日复一日 年复一年 #
# When it hasn't been your day, #
# 时运不济 活着受罪 #
# your week, your month, or even your year #
# 你我永不离弃 #
# but I'll be there for you #
# 你我相偎相依 #
# 'Cause you're there for me too #
（中央咖徘厅）
喝完后
Okay, so when you're done with your tea,
我会看你们的茶叶 帮你们算命
I'll look at the leaves and tell your fortune.
- 你会茶叶算命法    - 我这么做有好几年
- I didn't know you read tea leaves.     - Oh, yeah, I've done it for years.
后来我放弃 因为我算得太准了
I actually stopped because I was so accurate.
生命的乐趣之一…
You know, and one of the great joys of life...
就是不可预测性
...is its wondrous unpredictability, you know?
还有茶叶会让我拉肚子
And also, tea tends to give me the trots.
- 我好了 帮我算吧   - 好的
- Okay. I'm done. Read mine.     - Okay.
我看到一个梯子
Ooh. I see a ladder.
它的意思不是升职 就是暴力死亡
Which can mean either a promotion or a violent death.
我是主厨 我不可能被升职
I'm the head chef. I can't get promoted.
下一个是谁
Mm-hm. Mm-hm. Who's next?
我好了 帮我算
Okay, I'm done. Do mine.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 我看到一个圈圈
Um... Oh. Okay, I see a circle.
那表示你怀了孩子
Oh, which can either mean you're having a baby...
或你会做出科学发现
...or you're gonna make a scientific discovery.
我一直都待在实验室里
Well, I have been spending a lot of time in the lab.
- 你的茶叶又告诉你什么呢 菲比   - 好吧
- What does yours say, Pheebs?     - Um... Wow, all right.
我会认识一个男人 而且很快
Oh, I'm gonna meet a guy. And really soon.
他会是我的梦中情人
And he's gonna be the man of my dreams.
或许他不是我昨晚梦到的那个男人
Probably not the guy I had a dream about last night.
你
You.
嘿 有人看到我的衬衫吗
Hey, has anyone seen my shirt?
它是前开式的衬衫 淡鲑鱼色
It's a button-down, like a faded salmon color?
你是说你的粉红色衬衫吗
You mean your pink shirt?
淡鲑鱼色
Faded salmon color?
不 我没有看到你的粉红色衬衫
No, I haven't seen your pink shirt.
真是的 我一定把它丢在蒙娜家了 我就知道
Great, great. Then I must have left it at Mona's. I knew it.
我想你可以到安泰勒的专卖店再买一件
I'm sure you can get another one at Ann Taylor's.
它是我最喜欢的衬衫 我爱它
That's my favorite shirt, okay? I love that shirt.
请蒙娜把它还给你
Well, just ask Mona to give it back.
我不知道 或许吧
I don't know. I mean, I guess I could.
我们不算是好聚好散
It's just, we didn't really end things on such good terms.
我想去她家就得忘了她告诉我的一件事…
And if I went over there, I'd be ignoring the one thing she asked me to do...
她要我去跳楼自杀
...when we broke up: Jump up my own ass and die.
等一下
Oh, wait a second, you guys.
最近我走到哪里都会看到那个男人
For the last couple weeks, I've been seeing that guy everywhere I go.
我们搭同一班公车 去同一家书局 干洗衣店
We take the same bus, we go to the same bookstore, same dry cleaner.
或许他就是我的真命天子
Maybe he's the tea guy.
菲比 你看到了吗
Pheebs, did you see that?
他真的在看你 而且他很帅
He totally checked you out and he is so cute.
我的茶叶出现"乡巴佬"的图案 那是什么意思
Mine is a picture of the Village People. What does that mean?
- 嗨   - 嘿
- Hi.     - Hey.
- 嗨   - 嗨
- Hi.     - Hi.
茶叶让菲比拉肚子
Tea gives Phoebe the trots.
我以为乔伊跟我可以不尴尬…
I thought Joey and I would be okay once we hung out...
但我们不知道该怎么相处
...but it's like we don't even know how to be with each other anymore.
- 那真的很难 但情况会有改善的   - 你怎么知道
- I know it's tough, but things will get better.     - How do you know that?
如果情况恶化…
What if it just gets worse and worse and worse...
让我们无法共处一室呢
...to the point where we can't even be in the same room with each other?
我不善于给好建议
I'm not great at the advice.
要我讽刺你一下吗
Can I interest you in a sarcastic comment?
要起司吗
Some cheese?
甜心 为什么布鲁斯·史普林斯汀的CD
Honey, why is the Bruce Springsteen CD...
会放在凯特·史帝文斯的盒子里
in the Cat Stevens case?
如果我找不到正确的盒子 我会随手拿一个盒子来装
Let's just say if I can't find the right CD case, I just put it in the nearest one.
- 凯特·史帝文斯的CD在哪里    - 詹姆士·泰勒的盒子里
- Okay, well, where is the Cat Stevens CD?     - In the James Taylor case.
- 那张CD在哪里    - 我帮你节省一些时问
- Where's the James Taylor CD?     - Honey, I'm gonna save you some time.
那200张CD没有一张放在正确的盒子里
Two hundred CDs, not one of them in the right case.
好吧 不需要慌张 大家深呼吸
Okay. No need to panic. Deep breaths, everyone.
我们只需要把CD
Okay, um, we're just gonna have to spend some time...
放在正确的盒子里
...and put the CDs in the right cases.
那么做的话 应该能将CD排好
If we're gonna do that, we should come up with some order.
像是照字母或类别
Like alphabetically, or by genre.
不知道 我们得谈一谈这件事
Hmm, I don't know. We really have to talk this through.
天啊 你们真的有问题 我为你们感到难过
Oh, my God, you guys have such problems. I feel so terrible for you.
好吧 对不起
All right. Okay, I'm sorry.
你跟乔伊满脑子都是这件令人不舒服的事
Look, you and Joey, you're both focusing on this uncomfortable thing.
你应该改变一下话题
What you need to do is change the subject.
下次让他谈别的事
Next time you see him, try to get him talking about something else.
- 对 那挺有道理的   - 对啊
- Oh, yeah, that makes sense.     - Yeah.
或许你在工作上有问题 需要他的建议…
I don't know, maybe you have a work problem you need his advice on.
- 我可以那么做   - 很好
- Ooh, I could do that. I could do that.     - Good.
"迈阿密天龙"的原声带 真的吗
Honey, the Miami Vice soundtrack? Really?
那是唱片行的赠品
They were just giving those away at the store.
我得拿钱去换
In exchange for money.
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hi.
我真的不知道该跟你说什么
I really don't know what to tell you, Rach. I really don't.
或许乔伊可以帮你解决工作上的大问题
Maybe Joey could help you out with your big work problem.
- 什么    - 对 乔伊 她…
- What?     - Yeah, Joey, she's...
瑞秋工作上有个大问题 那真的很伤脑筋
Rachel's got this really big work problem. It is a head-scratcher. Heh.
你知道吗 我们想赶上晚餐预约 就得马上出发
Well, you know what? If we're gonna make dinner, we're gonna have to leave. Yeah.
你工作上出了大问题
So you, uh, have a big work problem?
对 那是…
Yeah. It's, um...
Yeah, it's, uh...
真的没什么
You know, it's nothing.
好吧
Oh. Okay.
我想我该走了
So, uh, I think I'm gonna take off.
不 乔伊 等一下 它真的很严重 我有问题 是…
No, wait, Joey, it is. It's something. It's, um...
是我的老板
It's my boss.
- 是吗    - 对 跟…
- Yeah?     - Yeah. And, um...
跟我的宝宝
And my baby.
是吗
Yeah?
我老板想买我的宝宝
My boss wants to buy my baby.
什么 我的天啊
What? Oh, my... Oh, my God.
我知道 我跟你说过了 这真的是个大问题
I know, I told you, it's a really big problem.
- 他要买你的宝宝    - 你能相信吗
- He wants to buy your baby?     - Can you believe that?
- 那太疯狂了   - 我就是那么跟他说的
- That's crazy.     - That's what I told him.
- 怎么会发生这种事    - 我会告诉你
- How did this even happen?     - Well, I'll tell you.
我老板跟他太太 他们不能生小孩 所以…
See, uh, my boss and, uh, his wife, they can't have children, so, um...
在圣诞派对上 我们碰到了面…
And then when we were at the Christmas party...
他喝醉了跟我说 "瑞秋 我要买下你的宝宝"
...and he got drunk and said to me, "Rachel, I want to buy your baby."
你说你老板跟宝宝有问题的时候…
Man. When you said it was a problem about your boss and the baby...
我以为你是指产假的问题
...I figured it was something about maternity leave.
对
Oh. Yeah.
对 那样子问题简单多了
Yeah, that would have been a much simpler problem.
- 哈罗   - 是你 我走到哪里都会碰到你
- Oh, hello.     - Oh, it's you. I see you everywhere.
我是吉米 吉米·尼尔森
- Mm-hm.     - I'm Jim. Jim Nelson.
吉米吉米·尼尔森 我是菲比菲比·布非
Jim-Jim Nelson. I'm Phoebe-Phoebe Buffay.
我们最近常见面
We certainly have been seeing a lot of each other.
的确 或许明天晚餐时 我们也能碰面 八点可以吗
We have. Maybe we'll see each other at dinner tomorrow. Say, around 8:00?
或许会吧
Well, maybe we will.
蒙娜
Mona?
好 如果我是鲑鱼色衬衫 我会在哪里
Okay, if I were a salmon shirt, where would I be?
抱歉我把酒洒到你的衬衫上
I am so sorry I spilled wine all over your shirt.
- 没关系   - 不 它还是湿的
- Oh, it's okay.     - No, it's still wet.
我把它拿去洗干净 免得留下印子 我有件衣服可以借你
Let me get it out before it sets. Oh, I have something you could wear.
拿去吧
Here.
我真的不想穿女人的衬衫
I don't know if I wanna wear a woman's shirt.
- 那是男人的衬衫   - 太粉红了
- No, no, that's a man's shirt.     - Awfully pink.
那不是粉红色
It's not pink.
天哪 甜心 我们注定要在一起
Oh, my God, honey, we are so meant to be together.
- 我们都有"安妮"的原声带   - 甜心 那都是你买的
- Look, we both have the Annie soundtrack.     - Honey, both yours.
谢谢你给我关于乔伊的建议
Hey, great advice on that Joey thing.
- 你是指工作的问题吗    - 它真的是太棒了
- Yeah, the work problem?     - It was perfect.
我觉得他又是我的朋友了
It felt like he was my friend again.
- 你说你有什么问题    - 那不重要
- What problem did you tell him you have?     - Oh, that's not important.
重点是 我想一切都会没事
The point is, I really think everything's gonna be okay.
需要我效劳吗
May I help you?
你觉得你可以买走我朋友的宝宝
You think you can just buy my friend's baby?
我们一直巧遇 真的很有趣吧
Isn't it funny how we kept running into each other?
那就像是有人要我们在一起
It's as if someone really wants us to be together.
没错 那就是我
Someone does. Me.
聪明的家伙 做的好
Ooh. Witty banter. Well done. Good.
- 跟我谈谈你自己   - 好吧 我是按摩师
- So tell me a little bit about yourself.     - Oh, okay. Well, I'm a masseuse.
- 我以前在这个地方工作…   - 你喜欢参加派对吗
- And I used to work at this place...     - Do you like to party?
我喜欢派对
I... I like parties.
你很狂野 对吧
You're wild, aren't you? Heh.
- 对 我猜是有一点   - 那没有什么 我也很狂野
- Yeah, I guess. A little.     - Ain't no thing. I'm wild too.
总之…
So, um, anyway...
我住在纽约 我猜那有点狂野…
...I... I've lived in New York, somewhat wildly, I guess...
我从14岁就住在这里
...for, um... Well, since I was 14.
抱歉 我盯着你不放
I'm sorry. I'm staring.
因为你有双最漂亮的眼睛
It's just that you have the most beautiful eyes.
别说了
Oh, stop it.
还有你的胸部
And your breasts. Mm!
好吧
Okay. Ahem.
听着 你有点太快了
Look, uh, you're coming on a little strong.
但我就疑中留情吧
But I'm gonna give you the benefit of the doubt.
因为宇宙要我们在一起
Because it seems the universe really wants us to be together.
我们为什么不开始呢 你可以跟我谈谈你自己
So why don't we start over, okay? You can just tell me about yourself.
- 好吧   - 好吧
- All right.     - Okay.
我写小孩子看的…
I write erotic novels...
色情小说
...for children.
- 什么    - 它们非常不受欢迎
- What?     - They're wildly unpopular.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
或许你会想知道 我有个博士学位
Also, you might be interested to know that I have a Ph.D.
- 真的吗    - 对 它真的很大…
- Wow, you do?     - Yep. A pretty huge...
够了
All right.
# 明天太阳依然升起 #
# The sun will come out tomorrow #
# 你可以十分肯定 明天 #
# Bet your bottom dollar that tomorrow #
# 会有阳光 #
# There'll be sun #
- 嘿   - 乔伊 听我说
- Hey.     - Hey, Joey, honey, listen.
谢谢你昨天跟我谈
Thank you for talking to me yesterday about that thing with my boss.
- 那对我来说意义重大   - 别客气 我得告诉你…
- That really meant a lot.     - Not a problem. Oh, and just so you know...
那家伙不会再为了宝宝的事来烦你了
...that guy's not gonna be bothering you about that baby thing anymore.
- 什么    - 就说我已经解决了问题
- What?     - Let's just say I took care of it.
我们得谈一谈
Ooh, let's say more.
别担心 我好好地跟他谈过
Don't worry, don't worry. I just told him, very nicely:
"你不能买别人的宝宝 别闹了"
"You don't go buying people's babies, so back off."
- 什么    - 什么
- What?     - What?
不 不
No, no, no.
乔伊 他不想买我的宝宝 那是我编出来的
Joey, he doesn't wanna buy my baby. I made that up.
什么 为什么
What? Why?
我们才有话题聊 不会觉得尴尬
So that we would have something to talk about so it wouldn't be awkward.
你想不出来别的借口吗
And you couldn't think of anything else?
你说你老板要买你的宝宝
You said your boss wants to buy your baby?
你居然对我老板大叫
I can't believe you yelled at my boss.
我会被开除 我该怎么办
I'm gonna lose my job. What am I gonna do?
你可以卖掉你的宝宝
You could always sell your baby.
我不敢相信你把我老板扯进来 我会被开除
Joey, I cannot believe you brought my boss into this. I'm gonna get fired.
- 你骗我   - 是她要我那么做的
- You lied to me.     - Well, she told me to.
钱德有两张"安妮"的原声带
Chandler has two copies of Annie.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
- 罗斯   - 哈罗
- Ross!     - Hello.
罗斯 你在做什么
Ross, what are you doing?
希望你们听了能够释怀 我没有自摸
Not touching myself, if that makes anyone less uncomfortable.
早安 你找我
Morning. You wanted to see me?
请进 坐下
Please, come in. Have a seat.
- 听着 塞纳先生…   - 让我先说吧
- Okay, look, Mr. Zelner...     - Oh, I think it's best that I speak first.
好吧
Yeah.
人事部的李将是我们谈话的见证人
I've asked Lee from human resources to be here as a witness to our conversation.
天啊
Oh, God.
如果我有暗示过你 我想买你的宝宝…
If I in any way implied that I wanted to buy your baby...
我很抱歉 好吗
...I am sorry. Okay?
上星期我问你 你的预产期是什么时候…
Last week, when I asked you when your due date was, uh...
我并没有要买你的宝宝的意思
...I certainly did not mean that I felt that I was due your baby.
我希望清楚地告诉你…
Yeah, I want to be very clear...
我了解 它是你的宝宝…
...that I understand that it's your baby...
我不能买下它
...and it is not mine to purchase.
只要把话说清楚就好了
Well, as long as we are clear about that.
到了
Oh, there it is.
- 这不是你常去的洗衣店   - 我知道
- That's not your regular dry cleaners.     - I know.
那个怪胎会去那里 我得找新的洗衣店
But that creep I went on that date with goes there so I had to find a new one.
我还得找新的录影带店 银行…
I also have to find a new video store, a new bank...
成人书店 杂货店…
...a new adult bookstore, a new grocery store...
- 什么    - 新的杂货店
- What?     - A new grocery store.
宇宙说我会认识一个好男人 那是真的吗
The universe said I was gonna meet a nice guy and that's what they gave me?
我上天堂后一定会痛扁他
When I get up there, I'm gonna kick some ass.
别担心 菲比 你会认识某人的
Don't worry, Phoebe, you're gonna meet someone.
如果我能找到好男人 你也可以
If I can meet a great guy, so can you.
对 我们都可以 也都会做到
Yeah, we both can. And we both will.
（布利克街干洗店）
- 你不必进来    - 你在开玩笑吗
- Oh, you didn't have to come in with me.     - Are you kidding?
他们在这把衣服洗干净 对我来说这就像是迪士尼乐园
This is where they get out stains. This is like Disneyland for me.
我要到这里看干净衬衫跳舞
I'm gonna be over here watching the dance of the clean shirts.
对不起 我想你掉了…
Oh, excuse me. I think you, uh, dropped...
什么
What?
抱歉 只是你真的是美得不可思议
I'm sorry, it's just that you're so incredibly beautiful.
我也这么觉得 但又能怎么办呢
Oh, yeah, well, I'm sorry about that too. But what are you gonna do?
别认为我疯了 但我觉得我是注定捡这个的
I hope you don't think I'm crazy, but I feel like I was meant to pick this up.
- 你相信那种事吗    - 有一点
- Do you believe in that kind of thing?     - A little. Heh.
你说的对
Now you're talking.
你要去喝咖啡吗
Would you like to go have a cup of coffee?
我很乐意 我去跟我朋友说一声
I'd love to. Let me just tell my friend.
是墨水印子 我能看你把它洗干净吗
Ooh. An ink stain. Hey, can I watch how you get this out?
她一定是离开了
She must have left.
- 嗨   - 所以呢 发生了什么事
- Hi.     - So, what happened?
没事了
It's all gonna be okay.
他们很高兴我不告他们
They're just so happy I'm not suing them...
我还能多放一个月领薪产假
...that they gave me one extra month paid maternity leave.
只要我知道那些钱绝不是…
So long as I understand that the money should not be construed...
这个宝宝或其他宝宝的订金
...as a down payment on this or any other child that I may bear.
罗夫·罗兰真的想尽办法…
Wow. Ralph Lauren is going out of their way...
要证明他们不是贩婴集团
...to show that they're not in the baby-buying business.
- 钱德 能让我们独处一下吗    - 抱歉
- Chandler, can you give us a minute?     - Oh, I'm sorry.
- 你要把我踢出我家的客厅    - 对
- You're kicking me out of my living room?     - Yeah.
我会在那里
I'll be in there.
乔伊 抱歉我骗了你 我只是希望事情…
Joey, I'm really sorry that I lied to you. I was just trying to make things...
我知道…
I know. I know.
方法还是有效
But it kind of worked.
我不知道你是怎么想的
I mean, you know, I don't know about you...
但我一直没想到我们的事
...but I haven't thought about our thing since all this.
你说的对 对
Yeah, you're right.
我们又恢复了朋友的样子 对
Yeah. It's kind of been like us again, a little bit.
- 对啊 我很想念那段时光   - 我也是
- Yeah, I know. I've missed that.     - Me too.
我没有想到 自己怎么会…
I mean, I haven't thought at all about how I put myself out there...
跟你说那些话 你跟我的感觉不同…
...and said that stuff and how you didn't feel the same way about me...
那真的很尴尬
...and how it was really awkward.
我的妇产科医生想杀我
My gynecologist tried to kill me.
编号是J437A
Item J437-A.
颜色 冬莓色
Winterberry.
嗨 听着 进来 进来吧…
Hi, um, listen. Come here. Come...
关于昨天的事我很抱歉
I'm so, so sorry about yesterday.
我真的很抱歉 那只是…
I'm really, really sorry. It's just...
听着 你不必道歉 我了解你为什么会去那里
Listen, Ross, you don't have to apologize. I understand why you were there.
- 真的吗    - 对 你还对我有感觉
- You do?     - Yeah. You still have feelings for me.
老实说 我也对你还有感觉
And to be honest, I still have feelings for you too...
我希望我们能复合 那是不可能的
...and I wish we could work out, Ross, but we can't.
你跟瑞秋还有宝宝的事 太复杂了 我只是…
It's too complicated with you and Rachel and the baby. I just...
那个人不该是我
It just wasn't meant to be.
天啊 你说的对
Oh, God. You're right.
罗斯 我们得坚强
Ross, we have to be strong.
好吧 我得走了
Okay, I'm gonna go.
我能留下它来怀念你吗
Can I? To remember you?
不行
No.